## Sam Ward-Pickering

Full-stack Developer

I am a full-stack developer and former business owner with a Bachelor's degree in Creative Technologies. I'm determined, reliable and I have a passion for learning, collaborating and helping others. I've been interested in programming ever since I studied computer science in college and I'm constantly thinking about the ways in which I can combine both my technical and creative skills to work on meaningful projects that positively impact others.

I recently graduated from Enspiral Dev Academy and during my time studying there I found my past experience as a business owner to be of great benefit. Having had prior experience managing a team I was able to create safe, communicative and supportive team environments in the numerous group projects I was a part of - as well as easily filling leadership roles if needed.

## **Experience**

Enspiral Dev Academy • Full-Stack Developer 2021 - March 2022

An immersive programming bootcamp that teaches full-stack development, agile methodologies, human skills and test driven development within a work-simulated industry environment.

- Full-Stack Development incorporating React, Redux, Auth0, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SQL databases.
- · Agile methodologies.
- · Test Driven Development (TDD).
- Human Skills such as: conflict resolution, giving and receiving feedback, active listening,
- · Group projects and peer-programming.
- · Version control tools such as Git and GitHub.

## **Pyramidion Studios** • Co-Founder

2018-2021

A multifaceted production company specializing in promotional material for businesses and organizations, music videos and ecommerce sales.

- Overseeing day-to-day operations.
- Customer support.
- Administration.
- · Market research & marketing.
- · Product innovation.
- · Content creation.
- Shipping and logistics.

## Contact

Mobile: +64 22 635 0956

samuel.wardpickering@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>Sam Ward-Pickering</u> GitHub: <u>Sam-WardPickering</u>

Location: Wellington

#### **Tech & Tools**

React, Redux, Auth0, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SOL.

Version control tools such as Git and GitHub

Fusion 360 & Blender; 3D Modelling software.

Figma; a wireframing and prototyping tool

Adobe Photoshop, Premiere, Audition. After Effects.

### **Skills**

### Self-motivated

I'm progress-driven and tenacious by nature. Feedback I often get from coworkers and collaborators is that I'm able to get a task or project completed without the need for encouragement or motivation from others.

#### Creative

I've always been drawn to anything and everything creative. In the past, whether working as a part of a team or during my time as a cofounder and company director, I found I was able to use my creativity to innovate, generate fresh ideas and think outside of the box to problem solve.

### Education

## **Enspiral Dev Academy**

Intensive 15-week work simulated programming bootcamp

# Wellington Institute of Technology (WelTec)

Bachelor's degree in Creative Technology.

#### Communication

I am a good active listener and I'm very open-minded to new ideas and the opinions of others. I am polite, articulate and self-aware and I'm naturally able to deliver a message or opinion in a concise and respectful manner.

## Learning

I am a very curious person and an eager learner and you'll often find me reading articles, reading books, listening to podcasts, watching videos or learning from others. There's always more to learn and knowledge is power!

## **Teamwork & Collaboration**

I'm very much a people person and I thrive in a team environment. I love working with others to accomplish a shared goal or objective while simultaneously building strong bonds and friendships. I'm emotionally intelligent, positive and supportive. I make an excellent collaborator and pair programming partner and my peers have described me as "an absolute pleasure to work with".

## **Other Experience**

Uncle Bills Wholesale • Shopfloor Assistant Nov 2020 - 2021

I worked as a part of a tightly-knit team and it was a great opportunity for me to hone-in my communication and conflict resolution skills. One major highlight for me was helping customers and putting a smile on their faces. I'm grateful for my time working at Uncle Bill's and having the chance to gain more hands-on experience in a customer facing job.

#### **The Warehouse** • Online Order Fulfillment

My employment at The Warehouse allowed me to utilise my organisational and collaborative skills as I was a part of a large team. This required a lot of co-ordination and planing as we were responsible for finding, packaging and shipping orders off to customers.

#### **Interests**

Films & Filmmaking
Photography
Philosophy
Long walks in nature
Psychology
Making music

# **Curricular & Extra-curricular Activities**

Scots College Young Leaders Conference.

Scots College Prep School Senior Leader.

Volunteer at US Embassy for underprivileged people.

Wellington Air Training Corps (ATC).

2017 - 2018

Volunteer at Kilbirnie Salvation Army store.

Volunteer at Film For Change NZ.

References

Available upon request